hey everyone welcome again to another
lesson in this Tosca training course
today instead of showing something in
Tosca
I'm going to answer the most frequently
Asked question at least in all of my
Tosca videos is related to a license for
installing and working in Tosca
now if you look at the tracentes website
they will tell you that they don't
provide any training licenses uh or any
trial licenses for Tosca right today I'm
going to show you another way through
which you can still obtain a training
license from placentis in order to start
working with Tosca so let's go through
the process
now if you have looked at one of my
earlier videos where I have shown you
the whole Tosca set up along with the
license
this process would almost look similar
right it's only
um the URL which you need to know in
order to get a training license request
so this is the URL this is the most
important part so you need to have a
support account in try centers right so
and then you need to go to this uh URL
which is support Hub present this and
then you have to put this ID equals to
training license request right so that
will take you to uh the URL where you
can request a trading license and you
can start working with Tosca again
but uh let's go step by step so the
first step is to have a support account
and try centers right so you need to go
to support hub tracentist.com
and then click on register if you don't
have an account already right so you
need to fill all the details so let's
start here with
filling all the details here
I will just fill all the required fields
which are present in this form okay
so let me
search for a time zone
and the most important part in this form
is the business email now there is no
alternative you have to provide a
business email you have to get this from
somewhere right
so I will put my business email here
and then we need to put a password here
okay
rest of the fields are not mandatory so
if you want you can fill but I don't
feel it's mandatory so I'll just go
ahead with the form
okay so our manifestation is successful
now I can go ahead and
login into the support portal for
presenters in order to get a training
license right
so let's go ahead and log in here
and once we log in it will take us
through
the support portal right
okay let me get rid of all these pop-ups
okay so we need to uh
verify our account before uh it can
really work right so go back to your
email box and then click on the link
which will verify your email right
I will do this in the background
so I have refreshed the page now and
that error should be gone because I have
verified myself through email right
and now uh The Next Step once you have
registered yourself in the trial Center
support portal
you need to go uh to that particular
link right which I have provided you so
this is this is the URL through which
you can access or you can request for a
training license to use Tosca or to
learn Tosca right
now there are two ways you can request
license or there are basically two
models uh that is the crowd cloud
training license and that is also
there is also a license which you can
install directly in your machine right
so if you want you can go through the
documentation how to connect to your
Cloud license server or what are the
license model
you can also go to downloads and you can
download your trash and testoster from
here right
but the first step is to uh request for
a training license and I would recommend
you to uh go for a cloud trading license
because you can connect it from anywhere
right
so I'm going to request a cloud training
license okay and it is currently showing
State as deploying so once it's
completed I would be having my training
license
okay
so you just need to refresh it okay so
once it is completed the state will
change
similarly if you want a on-premise
license that means directly on your
machine
um
you can request it here as well right uh
because my previous request is pending
or waiting for deployment I'm not able
to request a on-premise trading license
okay
but um I prefer the cloud training
license so I have a requested for a
cloud training license
similarly you can go for any one of them
either on-premise which is on your
machine or on the cloud right
so let's wait until uh this is completed
and then we will see how the training
license looks like
so once the process is complete you will
see the state will change to deployed
and that means your Cloud trading
license is now ready
now one thing to note here is cloud
training license is only provided by
transientists for training purposes so
you should use this only for learning
Tosca and not for anything else
right so once this Cloud trading license
is ready the only other step you need to
do is either download your trash and
testoster you can download the latest
version
and you can directly connect it to the
cloud training license
or else if you have already a Tosca
Commander version open Tosca Commander
go to Project
and go to license
there you will find different options
okay so here if you go to activate
you will see there is a connect or
activate option right so you can click
on connect and then you can select on
connect to Cloud hosted license server
click on OK and here you need to enter
your username
so the same username and password which
we used
to create a profile on the try centers
support portal right I'm not going to
click on OK right so once you enter the
username and password it should connect
you to the cloud training hosted license
server right and your Tosca should now
be connected to a trading license
version right so you should be able to
use Tosca for a limited amount of time
but at least that will give you an
opportunity to learn Tosca and Implement
what you have learned through various
other videos
okay
so this is how you can connect to Tosca
using the training license server
provided by Trac centers either you can
opt for a cloud or an on-premise license
uh you can also go through this document
which is quite useful uh it's present
here so how to connect to your Cloud
license server it provides you with the
same steps which I have shown you right
so you need to go here connect to Cloud
hosted license server and then enter the
same username and password which you
have used for your transientist support
portal
and that way you should finally get this
kind of a window where it will say that
you have successfully connected to the
license server and you can start using
your Tosca Commander
okay so that's all about how to uh
create your own Tosca training license
and how to connect it to your Tosca
Commander so that you can start using
Tosca and start learning few things
about this great automation tool so
that's all for this lesson and in the
next session I am going to show you more
interesting videos about this Tosca
automation tool so stay connected and
keep learning